Microphone on great.
Hello, everybody and welcome to build I hope you've had so much fun so far
...stuff.
And, I hope that you'll continue having fun after the session my name is an
assembly amer program manager with os security.
And, to the alongside...we're going to talk to-you about microsoft passport
and windows hello windows hello is a new biometric authentication windows...
and microsoft passport is what is going to replace your passwords moving forward.
So,...hello
...biometric authentication that allows you to have immediate access to
understand devices.
With windows hello you can use your face scan your finger
or scan your eye and be able to immediately recognize windows
hello supports application authentication can be used the access
enterprise contents and can also be used to authenticate within the browser experiences?
Windows hello obviously provides a much more.
Personal experience compared to passwords but...also more secure
the security of windows hello comes from a technology called microsoft
passport which I will talk about in the second part of the presentation
surface data windows tense supports three
types of biometrics fingerprint face and iris.
All these three
are recommended on all the devices with the supporting hardware and if
...developer...is working on
...biometric experience recommend that you actually integrate with
windows.
Biometric framework that allows your application to leverage
...windows and...experience for enrollment
and usage and also provides the same design language that the users are custom...
I think the best way to actually...hello is avi demos I
thing I'm just going to switch to this other computer gary sitting here it is a
...a laptop that I have already and role my face into it and I
will show you how windows have always tightly integrated to the device unlock
experience so let me switch to that device...the me locked is device.
So, the first thing that you notice is
as a new kind of feedback language on the...screen.
As you can imagine we won't have the camera on all the...
To scan for faces and the only do
...know the user wants to get authenticated and we do so we actually provide that
kind of feedback to the user so which we're seeing right now is the pc telling me
...cute way that is looking for my face you see that's kind of a small
...top...is scanning around and looking from a face what
you to keep in mind is at the same design languages actually lose for other by...so,
for example, if I have my if I'm using my finger a to often
to authenticate to my device...say I standard wrong finger
the same feedback languages use the finger you just use is not recognise,
for example, if I have to move my face away because it's too close to the camera same
languages used to provide that feedback as well.
So, it's a very person experience he makes the pc
way more closely to what users expects what I'm going to do nexus actually
...camera and you can see that how fast it would be to get
authenticated so as soon as I bring my face wallop...
So, as you can see this is a very research back to.
As you can see it's a very streamline experience
is very personal learning curve is very fast because we tell the user what to do it
...in a way that...need to add them to doing extra work.
Now the authentication with windows hello is not only limited to our
unlock your device as I mentioned...can also be used
in application authentication and what I'm about to show you in the next part of the
demo is how windows hello can be used in authenticated the user
and purchasing app so let me switch back to the device that I was using?
So, here I have...store app and I'm ready to buy a movie.
Sorry.
Okay,
so, the movie titles their horrible...number two and as soon as
...clean purchase which you...the camera which you see is that
I I'm going to be...to provide my windows hello...here I have the option of using my
fingerprint or continue using scanning my face so let me bring is
...can see again the same design...also use...telling me that the
cameras on is looking from my face and as soon as I bring my
face in front I get authenticated and this
...comes up that says...show you want to purchase this staking that...to create
...on file I didn't want to spend fifteen dollars to
bite the movie right now but you get the idea?
All right so let's go back to our slides.
So, this is basically the kind of experience you could expect with windows
televise very personal is very easy-to-use but obviously improvement
...was not the only goalie had in mind we want-to make sure that your experience
still preserve your privacy and is also secure from
a privacy perspective we want-to make sure, you know,
that microsoft never stores and image a few either on the device or
on the back and server we never ever...the application or the server
...trying-to authenticate you and more importantly we never
update your enrollment data without your consent in other words if you say
...room with a lot of people we don't want to make
...to use the other faces in the room to update
...a data which means that
your experience or reliability actually experience will be huge reduced you always in control
you can visit the setting page and you can enhancer enrollment data you can also remove
...data if you which we never do this automatically so
that's basically price from a security perspective our goal was to meet the enterprise
...security data is required by many after customers in the sector of government
have financial sector health stricter or...and what
we have successfully demonstrated is that are algorithms meet the
false acceptance rate that is required by socialization
false acceptance rate is the likelihood of somebody having random access
...device and being able to authenticate as you obviously you want to make sure that
the number is low the x the target was one
hundred thousand which we actually successfully achieved now keep in mind
that one could achieve a number of zero if you never ever let anybody in right and
that's still gives...false acceptance rate but it's not usable so there is another rate
...tightly...couple with this false acceptance rate called the
...rejection we basically that denotes how reliable and how loser
from the algorithm is this is a likelihood of...being the actual digit owner
...device being able to actually authenticate analog my own device?
So, obviously...to make sure that the likelihood of not of that not happening is very low and
that's what this weight is about so we have x we have demonstrated with the one hundred
thousand false acceptance rate default rejection rate is between two to four percent
so the likelihood of new being able to finish my authentication experience asher very high.
The other things in terms of security is that we provide liveness measure making sure that the
actual is the users physically present in front of the device we also provide
...spoof thing mechanism with windows hello and,
the lower part of this powerpoint you see that when you
hold the picture a few in front of the camera because we're using ir technology to scanned
...the cameras sees is basically a white picture...there's nothing
that you can register width you can also the same experience if you hold your phone or
your tablet in front of the camera as you can see they don't provide any data
...for the for the sensor.
So, it's a technology that is pleasant to use...preserve your privacy and
assumed the security requirement that is set by one of most...demanding
the one of the most a strict requirements...customers.
In terms of our device support all of the current can future fingerprint
...will continue to work with windows hello for
face all current and future until real sense three-d cameras will be
supportive within those hello and in general any device with
...ir censored meats the publish specks that we have will be support
...with windows...for iris they will be a set of devices coming
in the market within the next twelve months but more details on the actual
...requirements and, the support will be coming so.
So, as I mentioned beginning of this discussion windows
...provides a very four-way user experience for authentication
but it's also more secure compared to password and
they also eluded the fact that the security of windows hello comes from microsoft
password so in a second part of this
talk what I want to do is actually walk you through of what microsoft passport is
and how it's going to replace passwords moving forward?
So, microsoft passport is a technology that is based on the
to factor authentication we have been doing enterprise for a long-time and the...goal
...freud is to provide a way to get rid of passwords
...internet the problem with the passwords are passwords are inherently insecure and
...to use there are so many passwords that you have three-member which makes it
human impossible to remember and as a result users
start reusing a passwords across different website and what that means is that the user is
now vulnerable to attacks of fleck if one
...compromise then your passwords are actually leaked the chances of the
...password...different websites also high...if the other website
is super protected you...basically being compromise so
what microsoft passport dies is solve both problems in one shot
...the user experience but replacing all of your passwords with
only one for digit ping that you have to remember is actually device
...as well so use the same paint on locker device now you can use the same ping to
access your...and applications so it's much
easier to remember moreover it can also use windows hello
for user authentication which means that there's nothing for you to remember it's really natural?
Now you may ask how could...for digit...being more secure than a
password another explain this later but suffused to say that.
Knowing dipping is not enough to axis your account
the attack actually has to have access to a device which makes it more secure.
So, that's all the user experience problem the second problem with their password was the
root server attacks with microsoft password because uses the
...cryptography technology there's no reason to store...secrets on a server.
So, even once...compromises nothing in
...can be used to attack you and other websites.
And, this is what we call it a to factor authentication because
...device contains the private key half the kind of the
public compare that is used for authentication plus the ping ditching no
...to factors something you have your device as something that she
...european or something that you are your biometrics...provides
a to factor authentication for the user.
Our goal that was set with microsoft passport is to provide strong
user authentication for everybody we started with our own products with our
on identity's including assure ad on print median microsoft account
and proud to in outside...will be supporting microsoft passport at the release-time.
We've also try...hard to provide really easy access for developers to
use this framework kind of taking understanding from strong authentication in
the enterprise sector and bring it to the consumer and michael walk you through
...how easy it is to use this framework moreover
...have join fight elias which is a group of
...that care about user authentication
...want to movie to a place that is much better than password and want-to make sure that
the microsoft passport will be the referenced implementation for fighter two-point-zero
specks.
What that means is that ruby a variety of devices that...user can pick
distorted private key outside your own device and that provides an option for them
to customized experience that...want to have for
the authentication so that basically gives strong user authentication for everybody?
The...prop of microsoft passport for developers is also
huge with microsoft passport the cost that are
...associated with the passwords go away, for example,
the password compromises that whole thing is going to go away users forget their past
what you have to...for...to set that
...that also is not necessary because within those huddle there's nothing to remember.
Also with passwords service have to take extra
step to secure storing them under
services sensitive data and whenever you have to do stuff like
that means that you have to spend more money with microsoft passport your simply storing public
keys there's nothing secret about it you can even published and there's no
...that's basic another reduction in terms of the server...
From api support out as michael walk if you have now native api to do
strongest raf one which is fully...with windows hello
and, soon later this year will have support for javascript api.
Our involvement with find deal would allow us to come up with the standard...of javascript api
...that also works across other browser...not something only
...support.
So, that's basically the value proffer developers.
And, for users well it's basically the concepts that
you're familiar with the weighty see microsoft passport is simple for digit
...or using the by metrics through windows...
...these kind of gestures if you are
...is philippine we do this at this at the time of device...when the user
...a device for the first-time...get up they'll see a very simple
...for windows hello they can do this after the
...by visiting the setting page.
I will show you what the experience will look like at the time of device...to set
...here so in this case the user just simply
...new missy tablet or new pc and...see this
page that allows them to use microsoft account to authenticate so they
provide the username password for microsoft account and...page
...says hey passwords so yesterday we move to new technologies
called microsoft passport and way...tell this to the user is set up a simple
for digit...and trusts us...more...password there's a
lincoln that explains why of for digit ping could be more secure than a password which I
...take get into later if the user agrees to this.
...since...the type...for digit
...if they wish to take longer ping they can also do that and,
at this point microsoft passport is setup.
Throughout the demos that I showed you whether he was unlocking my device or purchasing
...app with windows hello what was actually happening on the back and was
that microsoft-dot-com was using microsoft passport for authentication
saying none of those flows might my
microsoft-dot-com password was being sent over the wire everything was based on as
symmetric key operations so let me go back to the same device that I showcase
...approaches and show you what it means to have...
Let's try to buy the...again so previously you saw previously you
...the windows hello gestures finger...or face
as you can see there is an option for ping right and this tells you that
in all of these gestures are equivalent when it comes to authentic...
end-user can decide which one to use depending on the scenario dream.
...this...right coming back to here.
So, I talked about this at the beginning of
this part of presentation as...for digit...is more secure than
a password so by now I think you have a better idea of how this works so there is
...symmetric key that is generation a device that is protected by p so for
...attacker to actually attack you they have to know the pain that
...use and also have access to the device where your private key...so that means that the
attacker has to have access to factors rather than...your password and
...why...is more secure some extra crypto manage here wouldn't hurt microsoft
passports supports talking to a security modular
device called pm or trusted platform module...image an interesting device because you
provides some really nice properties from microsoft passport first of all is supports what is called
an anti hammering it protects again...device to figure audio
...so if somebody has access your device and...to guess european it will slow them
down tremendously the key that are protected by the...
Are impossible to be stolen from that device and
...a different device so that means that if you have a mahler running in your system they cannot simply
...credential and...in this on different device?
The other thing to keep in mind is that the...is never stored
on a device or the server so if somebody has physical access
...hard-drive there's no directly for them to figure on your pins.
All...flashlight.
On the crypto.
This is actually the way I normally visualize microsoft
...the way I think about this is a folder
containing a whole bunch of keys for different accounts that you may half and,
this folder is locked and for you to
...any apt to unlocking a user gesture has to be provided this user gesture could be
...could be
psychopath their finger could be scan of the iris or could be their face it doesn't matter
...if you remember from the store purchase...all presented to the user at time
...authentication once user provide...right penal
...right iris the folder is now unlocked so the app has
no access to its key what we make sure is that the there's no there's a separation between these
keys...to applications fu and bar create
...that folder we make sure that none of them can access
...other key we also make...these
two applications cannot clue together and try to figure out or
mapped to users together so if you have...that foo dot com and
...dot com there's no way for these two service to figure out dour titus thing user?
So, that's a kind of...overall summary of what microsoft passport is and how
...looks let's summarize what we have seen so far so
we start with xp introducing the experience with windows hello and,
how the useable use it on locker device and perform application authentication
next-door purchase the...through about how it is more
...past what we talked about microsoft passport and how the keys are stored in the and,
all the crypto that is synergy between in the third part of the talk and this is where I would invite
mike to come to stage is we're going to tell you how us developer can leverage
...as you can see it's very simple is basically three-plus
...call and...all the experiences similar
...store purchase so with datum capacity to mike thank you for your time?
...says a new said we've introduced to this new thing
called windows hello which is our biometric framework and we combine it
with microsoft passport to give you a very personal but yet
...very strong user authentication that we hope you'll choose
to use overpass passwords now...
presentation we showed you how microsoft account which is our identity has
inc microsoft passport and windows hello into their technology
in their software so this last section of the this presentation is we
want to show you the developers how you can take this technology and easily
...the apps that you're going to be building for windows...
So, in this particular let's start the best way to do this is just show you an app that we've
developed and ...and this is a demo...that we've created and
we've taken the api that you're going to use incorporate those intoyour.
So, this is a simple little microsoft dynamics expense kind of
...that we've created as you can see here we get the familiar
username and password problem.
Now the username or password prompt is
today's story so unfortunately we can't just jump straight into using
microsoft passport so we have to use the traditional way of authentication right
now so in this particular app what you'll see me do is I'm going-to go ahead and type in my user name.
And, then I'll...are very long password
that I barely remember so as you can see in this particular app I have
to options here I can do start using microsoft passport or
sign in sign in is the traditional password authentication that we've been using
for last ten fifteen years right but what I can do
is I can say hey this absent giving me an opportunity to...something more
simple and more secure so with that what I'll do is I'll actually
tap the start using microsoft passport and what you're seeing in this demo is
actually the same user experience...you saw in a new xyz cyber microsoft
account is now asking me to use my fingerprint to
create a microsoft passport...these are actually the asymmetric keys and you spoke
of so this particular case I will take my finger place it on the?
you see of authenticated with microsoft passport using a fingerprint.
Again, is a new said these gestures that we have is whatever biometric
that combines with the micros of the windows biometric framework so this is how we can
do and authentication experience with using microsoft passport and you get windows
hello for free...it so let's take a look at what
actually took place in that app so let me switch back over to our powerpoint?
So, this is the actual flow that we use
...going to do what we call provisioning as I said that lasts.
And, the demo authenticated using my password because that's what
...all known do today so ideally the guidance years after you've done
your traditional password authentication and you up so that user to hey there's a
more simple more secure way of signing into the app we encourage you to use what we
call two-step verification process and there's really
microsoft passport doesn't confine your insisted you do that this is guidance that we
suggest to where you either send a text message to the phone it gives them a
coded type in or you send a security question to the screen and make sure that the user
...enrolling in this new secure at this new experience is actually the user
who is actually...this particular
...identity now the great thing about this is that once they've done this then they go to
create the microsoft passport and years the great thing as a new said microsoft
passwords bound by asymmetric encrypt cryptography.
What we have here is we have the workhorse of the api that you're going to use
and the universal windows platform is the key credential manager static class that
...providing with windows chat?
And,...this static clash you we creating method call request create a
...this is the api that you use in your apps to create
a microsoft passport key set for your application the simple thing about it
...is we pass...account id which can be any kind
of string that's familiar or works with your application you can then take this account
idea the string and you can persist that and
your applications data because it's not really a secret only your app can open it because of the
...a key isolation that a new spoke about...it really does is it makes a simple way for you to
retrieve the key later without having to worry about storing
...secrets on that disk or persisting any kind of
...once you do this create request create a...then what's going to
happen is basically you can get back an object that we call a
...key credential and this is basically...easy way to remember
is a credential that's based off of keys rather than passwords so in
this key credential what you have is that we have a private key which we never
let you really...because there's no reason
...see in the next demo but then we have a public key as we said this public key
is what allows you to authenticate to the server using this technology so in that public
key we're going-to go ahead and export that public key from your key credential and
we do that really simple by...public key is a very simple method returns back-up lava
data that you'll send up to the server now there's an interesting point here we...make sure,
you know, about is that when you register...public key with
the server the key thing here is that how you send that data
...the server is totally in your control microsoft passport doesn't make you
change your transportation protocol the something different you can use the same protocol that
...been using in your app all along you just sending different data using
that same protocol the other point to make here is that because of the security
properties of microsoft passport where we can actually use the t pm...hardware bound these
keys that when you having public key that you're going to
register that public key with the account on the server...if the user has four
or five devices the...going to have to change the back-end a little bit to make sure that it
can accommodate multiple public keys because those keys would have different devices
are different those devices will have different
...so what we have here is that we need to make sure that on the server back-end what
you do is that you make sure that your server can support
...number of public keys for each account that is on there.
So, now let me go back to
the application again and let's look at how we can use microsoft passport to sign it.
So, as you can see I'm in my app again I'm going to go sign-out.
And, as you can see the app we virtual for the
...it's now microsoft passport...can see that I've actually register
...using microsoft passport and I'm now ready to actually perform
authentication using microsoft passport so what I'm going to do here is I'm going to actually touch
online user tile and I get the same experience again I have what's happening here is
it's like okay I need to get this key
and that imaginary container that a new showed you in...one diagram alimony get
...your gesture to unlock that container so what I'm going to do is go ahead and push.
Okay,...you can see by fingerprint a...of container
and then actually authenticated using microsoft passport no way that I
...a password hash or anything like that or even and
provide a password let's take a look at how we accomplish that.
So, in usage.
Told you before we had a really simple api set where we have again,
a key credential manager which is the class static classes you're going to
used to implement this technology in your apps in there we have a very simple method called open
a sink the account id that you passed in the create is the
can id you used to retrieve your key credential that you've creepy...created so in your app
you'll actually go and say hey let's open up the key and then what's going
to happen is that the...going to send a challenge to the application basically the
...request a challenge data saying I'm about
to authenticate send-me a challenge the data that the server...opaque to the your
app your app doesn't need to know anything about that data however the server has a choice to includes
some security properties and if they want to such as a time-delay of to make sure that the
challenge is only good for so long you can't just sit there and keep holding on to
...so you use your protocol to send this challenge.
And, then basically what you're going to do is you're going to take this challenge and you
can ascended into this request sign a saying which is a method
off of the key credential that we give you when you open the key what we do there
is that basically when you call a request sign asic not only do we open the
container.
Wait for your gesture
prompt all the biometrics there but once we get permission to
...container get the key...then going to go ahead and sign all that data with
affect key and then output of that is going to be a signature of the actual challenge that
was sent to the server sent from the server so all the biometrics
that you saw whether it's face iris or fingerprint all
of the on-screen dialogue that you saw and then actually all the cryptography that you
saw is handled by this one single api because we've heard time and time again
that cryptography is hard and we want to make
this super simple so you guys can use it very easy very
simple to use once you have your signature again using your protocol you send
this signature to the server once the server has it they use the public key
that they you register previously that public key then is used with the signature
and the challenge and you basically validate that particular piece of data if it
confirm that your private key actually sign the data then you get authenticated you issue
...tokens as you would normally in your app and life moves on and nothing about your
...thing else about your app stays the same you don't change anything else so we're
only basically changing the authentication mechanism that the app uses we're not changing anything
else and you're getting all the biometrics and all...cryptography for free?
So, we have one more scenario will show you an that demo
...me get to that and that is that we have a delete scenario that we need to show you.
So, energy delete scenarios occasionally we get new
devices so when we get a new device we might want to take the keys are microsoft
passport office device because we're going-to go ahead and get a new so what we need to do
their is we actually need to provide a wage where we can remove
that particular key from the device so in our app here we've given you an option here
words basically says forget me and that's our basic little
catch phrase to say hey I don't want to use microsoft passport on this app anymore so
...we'll do from there is will simply say
okay let me hit forget me as you can see I'm no longer enrolled
in microsoft...the app the app is seen that I've deleted the key
and therefore I no longer have that persisted in the app so then if I wanted to
use microsoft passport again I would simply follow provisioning steps that I did
previously and then use that key to go ahead and sign in as we did before so
it's very clean very easy-to-use unless...that flow of what that looks like.
So, as you can see here here's the deletion flow and it's very similar the other
once again we're going to use open asic and I'll give you
a hint why we're going to open a...is because sometimes you may
...actually inform the server that you're about to get rid of a private key
...server really doesn't need to uses public
...so this is more of a good hygiene of key management we want-to make sure that
the server and the app and...as much as possible so what we do here is
we basically say let's open the key you use the
...public key like we did in the provisioning step and then which
...your hold onto that public key and then you'll call this simple api called delete
...passing in the same friendlier the account name or found id string that you did when you
do create
...open and then basically that will delete the key once you confirm that the key is
deleted on the local side then you can go ahead and send using your own protocol
send that public key back-up the server which point then the server can manage the public key on his side
howard's...to it can either tombstone the key and keep it around working go ahead and delete
the key whichever prefers?
So, there's a couple other use cases here that we want to touch on and
these use cases are basically these cases come into the
senses like okay well maybe I don't want authentication but I want this
idea of consent and...consent is basically this is that I'm writing
and app and I just want-to make sure that the login user
of that app is actual person who's about to do this specific action that the
you apps going-to-take place so the example I gave is that you have
...doctor and hospital who's doing rounds for
patient and we want that doctor to be able to have is device
and he's going from patient to patient to patient any signing in...these and finally hits a
...where the patient needs...narcotic so he's going to in
throughs medical app is going to sit there and try to prescribing narcotic for this particular patient but we that's
a trusted action we just don't want anybody doing that because a nurse and orderly found
in open device...they're ready to do this so what you can do
is you can ask for consent before actually triggering a committing that transaction
to order that particular prescription...this will do is what we've provided this
is we have a user consent verify a class that we introduced
...windows private previously
...before windows ten and in that class we've actually inserter
windows hello into that class to where you can get all the biometric framework and support
suit and experience that you've seen here today but you're not really authenticate
...to back-end server of any...time you're simply saying I want to
ensure that the login user to windows is the actual same user who's about to
perform this action and in that case you'll get the same prompt experience except
...basically make sure that the fingerprint or the pin that they use is the same one that
they've enrolled with an windows.
If you are interested in federated...
meanness federated is that you have an application to where you use
microsoft account or act as you're active directory as your identity to
your app or your third-party identity provider where you're going to
write applications to where you are others to use your identity then what we would
strongly suggest is that there's a session a tama sessions seven nine single sign
...was secure authentication and what they'll do is tell you how you can get this single sign
on experience using the api
that you've seen today but in the context of a more
...federated environment where your and allow other people to use these identity's
and actually or you're going to can...app to where you're going to use someone else's identity?
So, what we've done here today is we've gone over microsoft passport
...showed you that it's non fashionable because we're getting away from the passwords
is staff resistant because we have public keys and not
passwords secret stored on the server we're using strong user authentication not only
are we using public key cryptography but we're also using to factor off where
...I have to have my device and I have to know your gesture whether
that be pin biometrics of any kind whatsoever?
We've also talked about how we built-in support for windows hello
straight inside microsoft passport and with
their built-in support you write your app one way and then you get all the flavors
...support...whether you have password are where you have pin with you have
biometric such as face iris or fingerprint you don't have to rewrite your
app no code change you get that all by the three api is that we've showed you today was
also done a lot of diligence and making sure that these api
...simple we really understand that we want to make
the simple use and we understand that not everybody's a...and not
everybody's biometric engineer so these api is you have no
knowledge of crypto knowledge of biometrics you're going to go the api so just work
...easily carvel and I certainly is we understand changing a protocol is
expensive changes expensive regardless so we wanted to minimize the amount of change that you need
to do to quickly start using microsoft passport so with that change what
we've decided to do is we say okay no protocol changes whatsoever you use your
own transport protocol just send the data to the server how are you need to
and we try to minimize the number server changes that need to occur on the back-end.
We have a couple resources that we want to share with you to allow you to get started
using these featuresmicrosoft passport api
is these are in our windows security credential name space you'll see key credential manager
I'm pretty much any their classes that are prefix with key or these associated particular
ones and these are actually be available now in your
the build we have a couple related sessions that should have some sort of data that
talks about actually microsoft passport and how to manage those one of
the immediately after this one which is a managing mobile devices application and
prize they may have some actual information their on how if you're in enterprising
your seeking this how might be able to manage this particular information for your enterprise
and then obviously if you're federation you're writing a federated app or
yourwriting your...identity provider and you want to federating?
Then you want to check out session seven nine single sign on with secure of education.
The other thing is we my new shun I will be in the windows desire allowance
a directly after this particular session so if you have any other questions or just like
to chat with us we've we'd love to talk to-you will be in the export zones from
...fifteen for fifteen on thursday and
...we do a shorter version of this it's a little bit more what's a lot more
compressed we do that particular presentation on thursday one to one-thirty in the theater
...friday one one-thirty at the sears well and finally we
...make sure that if you have any question that we didn't cover either in the presentation or
in any of this time that we have allowed to talk to you that we
want to make it easy for you to get your questions answered so we've created...a
email address where you can say ask microsoft passport and with that please by
...send...any question we didn't get too or if you didn't have a chance to get with us one-on-one and
...mourn happy to actually answer those are get
...information uni so with that what I'd like to do is bringing
...back up on the stage and weakens answer any q...a that-you guys may half?
...yes.
That's correct yes.
Server.
Protect your app locally in what context.
Ok, so, the question to encrypt we this doesn't providing encryption this is just
...authentication mechanism right now so basically is if that
tax data if it was stored in
on a server per say then what that you could use this technology
...that instead of typing in a password to get into your
app to access the data you would use this technology of over a
...that way you would authenticate with the server and then you could pull your data down?
Correct there...is not for encryption.
Strictly as signature.
In the.
...coming...will be required to
...windows hello how are we do provide ways for enterprises to manage the complexity of the
pain so they can basically make is such that the
...is more complex and it could be alpha numeric this session that my
...after this...dives into stuff like that so...can deacon check...
Samoa.
...password
...how did you measure the failure rate for the of...
So, I think for data will like you to...to send an e-mail to microsoft
...passport question the data that we use
iced changing and I want to provide the most accurate point you send us a questionsince you
did data sample but it's more than thirty thousand samples if you use ...for
million plus combinations but if you...the actually...provide you...good what kind
can what kind of control...have over what are the aloud authentication mechanisms
of the are protecting the key and what kind of extensibility is
there given at the five-zero definitions allow custom providers you can say
...several only except and assertion if you do xyz?
And, suppose I have a strong scenario where I need to use a custom authentication mechanism
like a and fc device and I want to say look I want I'm going to
require the scan here and only of that one works you
...my server...right yep absolutes a great question and I want to break...
to pieces you brought up two different topics here the first one is about the gestures that are
allowed for the user ...five-to-two point always a new working group with
confided has been created we actively looking at a similar problem and
how to basically close down on a policies and gestures...so that's
...work-in-progress and...a team within that group that is looking at it as
a mission once we have to specks finalized make sure...microsoft possible will be reference
implementation...so that's the first part of your question but yes absolutely have to address that
...you ask about ok so if I have other devices that have
my private key how would windows intricate with them not quite
...relying on the t pm to protect the key that it's just a different mechanism instead of a
pin or a biometric to...that key so it's extensibility in
...if you remember the beginning of this I discussed the integration with windows
a biometric framework so if it's...if something that is
...it then it will be supported outside that...go...that are
not biometric we want to have another physical token device and say look if someone...a possession of this
token I'll write you can use the nfc api to xyz I will I do
my own authentication say yes the user this is the correct user I unlocked
...go I see...thinking for the most
...releases that whatever gesture we discuss you are the only supported
...we'll support scenarios where the gesture ditch you mention and the key
...remote device ...also something...looking at but
...combination...gesture comes from a different device and...and atp and that's not something that we
...immediately support...well, actually that...half-white question
...we have my question is also on the local scenario,
for example,
say that I have an external product...disk drive and I want to
tie into this system for user...you can't just take the driving...
and any random computer and access it...drive-in and want to leverage this method
authentication before allowing accesses or any method to do that for local device rather
through a server so we see local device
...stating that this is almost like a hard-drive that you want to
...usb external hard drive, for example?
The framework that we discuss here is basically providing crypto primitive and...sit
...the work to tied up the windows lock on with it safety
...authentication path none of
...it will not work so.
In other words let's say that external hard drive
...hacked some keys that are known by microsoft
cap or horatio rate and...the case if you plug...into an in your
future what you could do is to make sure that can access staticky over usb
...if it's something locally that's basically the remote and
...authentication snide however if you want to perform authentication
...hard-drive that's not something I will be supported by dasi
...unless dehydrate comes up with his own custom applicant at application...leverages
...microsoft passport otherwise...be supported questionnaire...
just two questions one is this time to...pm device
...within ritz...this on the buses the empty pm and also to invite
moved...cards with that supported so the second part of your question?
So, I'm not sure if you're familiar with the...smart cart work that video-only
...this framework no-contest stack so
...and next thing compacted at any will basically what it...to...
now ported to microsoft...the first part of your question I didn't quite follow would you mind
...get...the I was just saying...tights to...a
...market...pm all will as work on hardware that...I see
deep microsoft passport technically could without hardware in that case we're basically
rollback to software however we do pull white policies for enterprises to
...in which case the key creation will simply fail so that's something that
enterprise can manage but for consumer we...by default.
...basing three-d cameras support the windows...so you could
I ask about the device also quite a while...sweetly...support.
...the...camera still as far as...and ir camera that nissan
...yes the answer is yes.
What described...javascript...api
...supported some process is only microsoft browser crumble
assumption so the question is about javascript api and what browser
...support as...the part of fighter and...make sure that the javascript
...wb implementing windows ten will be based on this centers on accepted by other
browsers so...a goal for us to make sure what...the...with actually works with other...
I think one middle here go ahead.
the question is if the user...this device what's the story with the passwords you can simply
changer passport but what about microsoft passport
and the answer to that is eighty-something that the survey can provide imagine there is a portal for you to go
...that a device has been lost the server has a notion of what keys were
stolen that device so at that
...can simply move the key associated with that device from the set off the
keys...socially that user so if somebody has access to
...and for some reason they know your...they cannot...because...server rejects.
So, the question is there any device id...maps the
keys stored on the server with the device the answer is yes and
no yes in the sense that we have capability
...that allows a server to verified that the keys...
pm quality pm key atis st knowing the sense that I anything
al did this in one of the slide we want-to make sure that...cannot track
...kind of experience...so what we do is actually we create the
frame type of atis st for different I into providers situated
providers cannot...you to the same device so, it is...in...sense that we socratic
...is nobody can tie together.
All I see...yes the browser has enough notion to identify to device tuna
from the way she can say...he was my laptop that was...and they can provide to option
...your laptop was your phone was your pc so there is that thing that.
This is something that the browser can this
...we haven't been have to browsers three yet but the idea is that you get some kind of
...and maybe some...in that use you can pick and...way to tracking.
The samoa.
So,... going back to answer alee provided if there is a browser if there's a web portal
for you to go and report that you lost your surface in this case what the survey can do is
to because it knows which keys was...surface can simply move that from the list of trusted
...for you so you can continue using your other devices and this is one nice
thing about microsoft passport it allows you...device kind
of replication where you don't have that with the password if you lose one of your devices and use
your password on it you have to change your password with microsoft passport all you have to do
...reporter lost device that key...saluted the remainder of
the keys will continue to work and has...said because every device has a separate key then you
are the keys are still...and you don't have to change them psychosis
...finish up to what...alluding to
...is that this is a server experience because at that particular point of
devices gone right so this portal experience are describing is something that you
...to think about...I've lost a device so that particular case you're
not really tracking the device for the purpose of all I want to be able to start, you know,
trying to collect ad data or something like that it's...says is that hey,
you registered this public key from device a if you ever lose device a than
that server that identity provider would basically say okay here's our portal if
you lost my device then you tell us the name of your device or you give us some sort of hint of
what device you lost and then we on the back-end can say okay that public
keys and personas non god at that point so that's kind of the experience when you
...lost device experience there?
...directory stuff is the use of...or...
And,...is correct will be new server require depending on the it's a fairly complex
conversation...thing like you if you can...to ask a msr
...will definite provide you with other
...apologies I want to...question just to make sure you get the right answer?
That's correct okay so the community so
...excellent question so I don't know if the...work so basically the question was ...
then offline scenario what how do you accommodate for the offline scenario
...the servers are not online and
it basically again this is a concept that the identity provider owns in
the sense that we all know the basic go asf hand-shaking how this works and you get back
...token right so some of these identity fryers give you token that
has some sort of time to live which basically is like as long as you have this token
then basically, you know, if...offline they'll still reuse it but most of time the
reused in order to try to bootstrap another log on when you first come online
so this is really microsoft passport doesn't have any
notion of online offline it doesn't care in that sense because it's expecting
an online experience what you do after you've done the initial authentication is totally
...of the identity provider and they can
provide a better experience fern offline sign in versus an online...
Authentication.
Windows hello unlocks that basically windows
...unlocks the is the gesture used to unlock access to
the keys that are stored locally the gesture itself is never sent to the server.
No, they're actually rsa twenty forty-eight the asymmetric
That wrapped in tian so that way if you try to move the key
to another device is not going to work as...t pm king understand.
the question is can you set...multiple panes on the system and the answer
today is ...is that possibility but not in the
concept that-you had in mind is more between separating your personal stuff from
...stuff so that's possible ...be to the philippines for that the
scenario you may shun the way we recommend that you do it is would-be...to set up account
...child and they can hafta on...support...
That's a great question and it...you to send an
e-mail to the ask imis passport ...too I don't have
...by...and...question.
...speak to the camera adoption like the hardware
...working within the hardware industry to have cameras
...support ir...familiar by make the assumption that
...partner wrong that this camera in my pocket is not.
So, what we had in this slide is official answer we get provide at this point a bit
...more details on this will be consume so you need to...but
you are correct camera in your pocket most likely will not work because it relies on infrared technology?
Meaning and saucepan...you can't share...what integer to what's going with.
...some application I like...idea store.
Or of domain for server is the same...
So, the way we looked at this is we wanted to make showed that the data
...stored with the key...the things that are immutable...
To make sure that we don't stir things that needs
updating later on domain name is one thing that...support...please
...from wrong here passing domain namefor the key to be support any...
Deep id...just...opaque part...passes and...their notion of how the
attacking scissor yet the id part is just think of it is entropy there's
...underneath the covers there's a lot more stuff that goes into the key
but a think of it is user provided entropy that makes that allows you to ensure that
it unique so basically if you just had that and you looked into the covers the key
name is going to be something totally unintelligible to you but because you provided the
...when you do your creation
then we can use that in addition to the algorithm we used to create a keen
...to make sure that that's the online key that whatever have that.
Android apps should use the app aidid.
Browsers should use the...
Retail...origin ok so in for what we use
with this particular api set we use the app id.
So, I think I think I know the answer ok
...take this so the I believe we're getting at things like
...the ability to map and app to a domain name and,
this is against something at the five-to-two putting all these were looking at as we
speak and we you will
...that decision conclusive come up with...so for now the only isolation you
provide a is because you only support apps creating keys in
the microsoft passport is basic isolation between the apps which to have enabled
the browser scenarios to create keys and once you get to that point hopefully find a
...will be settled down so there will be a way to kind of address which
...product...something we need to...national this question?
No,
the good thing about that is because that's the consumer side and we don't have any in policy that
says on use hardware it actually works no matter what if there is a
t pm people leverages if there's no t pm
who simply rollback the software so that you...to the user
...believe you have to be online...of course...
Sure, so, we didn't highlighted in here but if you go look at
the actual api and name space we have a way to get access st data
...st data you can use to you can use that as st data to see if you
actually provision the key and...pm versus it's not.
Yes.
So, actually we did a lot of research on that and one of the things that you have
implementing windows ten is what is called the regeneration
pool so what we do is we actually start creating keys ahead of time and we have a pool of
keys ready for the app...and every time and apps claim one we try to create another one and
...grady so with...achieved a performance that is seems like really.
So, the question is sever often vacation and one thing that might brought up is microsoft passport
and api are basically crypto primitive as to what you do with it how
excusing how...use it for talking to a survey's totally depend on the application
obviously reclaiming using sl things like certificate...and things like
that but this is something that the application has to decide microsoft hospital care.
That's correct, yeah, it's the...you choose how you want to ensure that you're hitting the right endpoint.
Okay, ninety guys...guys...